<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<modDesc descVersion="100">
    <author>Ritter</author>
    <version>1.0.0.0</version>

    <title>
        <en>Adjust Animal Food</en>
    </title>

    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[Why shouldn't chickens eat oats if you want them to? Or make grass more effective for cows?
This mod gives you control over food effectiveness, crop assignments, mixed feed recipes, TMR compositions, serial/parallel consumption, and food consumption speed.

Supports multiplayer.

Notice:
- Customizations are done by editing an XML file generated in your savegame folder. No in-game UI is provided.

Features:
- Add custom food groups to animals and custom ingredients to mixtures/recipes
- Disable unwanted food groups or ingredients (except Grass)
- Adjust food effectiveness and feeding behavior (productionWeight, eatWeight, consumptionType)
- Change which crops belong to each food group (fillTypes)
- Modify mixed feed recipes and ingredient proportions
- Customize TMR/forage recipe compositions and ranges
- Control serial/parallel consumption and consumption speed (0.01x to 100x)

Limitations:
- Cannot disable Grass food group - causes game hang
- Cannot add/delete animal types or mixtures/recipes
- Consumption multiplier auto-disables with incompatible mods

Usage:
- Configuration file (aaf_AnimalFood.xml) is created in your savegame folder on first save
- Edit the XML to customize, changes apply on every load

Documentation and source code at https://github.com/rittermod/FS25_AdjustAnimalFood

Changelog:
1.0.0.0:
- Stable release (no functional changes from 0.12.0.0)

0.12.0.0:
- Added food consumption multiplier (0.01x to 100x) to speed up or slow down how fast animals eat
- Consumption multiplier is opt-in (disabled by default)
- Auto-disables consumption multiplier when known incompatible mods detected
- Bounds validation with warning and clamping for invalid multiplier values

0.11.0.0:
- Change animal feeding behavior between SERIAL and PARALLEL consumption modes
- Reorganized XML documentation with brief readme and comprehensive guide at end
- Quick-start examples for common customization tasks
- Improved XML readability with cleaner configuration section

0.10.0.0:
- Added custom content support: add food groups to animals, ingredients to mixtures and recipes
- Custom additions persist through save/reload cycles
- XML order preserved for food groups (affects UI display)
- Automatic validation and normalization of custom content
- Full compatibility with map-added content

0.9.0.0:
- Added disabling feature for food groups and ingredients
- Generated XML files now include inline documentation and examples
- Disabled items are preserved in XML across save cycles
- Automatic weight/ratio normalization when items are disabled

0.8.0.0:
- Added multiplayer support
- Improved code stability and performance
- Bug fixes and optimizations

0.7.0.0:
- Initial beta release
- Complete animals/mixtures/recipes support
- XML merging with game defaults and updates
        ]]>        </en>
    </description>

    <iconFilename>icon_adjustAnimalFood.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>

    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/main.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
</modDesc>
